Finding Aid for the George Alexander Heard Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 149)
  - Assorted Papers re: Political Behavior Approach (Box 164)
  - 1st Draft: Memorandum re: Ford Foundation & Goals of Program (Box 164)
  - Area Two (9/21/52) (In Yellow Box) (Box 164)
  - Assorted Papers re: Prisons, North Carolina Penal Institutions & Road Camp Prisoners (Box 164)
  - Prison Study File (Box 164)
  - Ford Foundation: Area Two Advisory Committee (Box 164)
  - Transcripts of Interviews re: Politics, Campaigns, Democratic Party (July 21 - October 20 [Year?] (To Alexander Heard from EHR) (Box 164)
  - PBC (Political Behavior Committee (Box 164)
  - Brookings (Box 164)
  - Champion, John W (Box 164)
  - Easley, Owen: M.A. Thesis (Box 164)
  - Holroyd, Keota (Box 164)
  - Res. Asst. & Grad. Stud. Applications (Box 164)
  - Selman, Jack: Ph.D (Box 164)
  - Fireman, Visitng (Box 164)
  - Agger, #2 (Box 164)
  - Country Club, Chapel Hill (Box 164)
  - Correspondence: RCM (Roscoe C. Martin), Department of Political Science, Syracuse University (Box 164)
  - Moos Seminar (Box 164)
  - So. Politics: Post-Publishers Clippings (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 42: Am. Federation of Labor (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 41 (Box 165)
  - Methodology (Box 165)
  - Democratic Presidential Election Newspaper Clippings (1952) (Sen. Estes Kefauver, TN & Sen. Richard B. Russell, GA) (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Alabama (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Arkansas (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Florida (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Georgia (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Louisiana (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Mississippi (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - North Carolina (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - South Carolina (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Tennessee (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info. (1952) - Texas (Box 165)
  - Newspaper Clippings Democratic Info.)1952) - Virginia (Box 165)
  - New York Times Special Edition: Forty-Nine Presidential Nominations, 1852-1940 (Box 165)
  - Politics: Georgia (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 121: The Government of England Notebook, W. A. Robson, UNC (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 42: UNC Student Quiz Books (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 43: Examinations (Box 165)
  - Pol. Sci. 43(?): Lecture Notes (On Index Cards) (Box 165)
  - Pol. Part. Paper (1952) (In Blue Box) (Box 165)
  - Copy of Election Returns: State of Mississippi, November 4, 1952 (Box 165)
  - Election Returns: Maine, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, Tennessee, Texas, Georgia (Box 165)
  - "A Study of the Presidential Vote: November 1948 - A National Survey" (Institute for Social Research, University of Michigan, April 1949 (Box 165)
  - Publications re: Polling Statistics, Book Manuscript & Miscellaneous (Box 165)
  - Assorted Loose Leaf Pages of Political Statistics, Book Manuscript & Miscellaneous (Box 165)
  - Advisory Committee, School of Public Health, Indian Project (Box 166)
  - The Washington Lobbyists - by Lesfer W. Milbrath (Box 166)
  - Refugee Relief Program (Box 166)
  - Aging (Political Behavior) (Box 166)
  - Citizenship Clearing House: New York, May 23, 1961 (Box 166)
  - Citizenship Clearing House: St. Louis Meeting, September 5, 1961 (Box 166)
  - Citizenship Clearing House: New England (Box 166)
  - American Heritage Foundation (Box 166)
  - Junior Science Symposium (Box 166)
  - Kenan Appointments (Box 166)
  - Community Chest (Box 166)
  - Am. Society for Public Adm (Box 166)
  - Pulbication: "The Negro and Employment Opportunities in the South" (Box 166)
  - The Second Corning Conference: Corning, New York, 1959-60 (Box 166)
  - Political Economy Conference (Box 166)
  - Purks, J. Harris (Box 166)
  - A.H.: National Municipal League - "Model State Law" (Box 166)
  - A.H.: Brookings Institution, 1958-61 (Box 166)
  - Carolina Women's Council (Box 166)
  - A.H.: Eagleton Foundation, 1959-60 (Box 166)
  - The Costs of Economy - by Alexander Heard (2nd Draft, 7/29/59) (In Blue Box) (Box 166)
  - Assorted Desk Supplies & Travel Clock (In Blue Box) (Box 167)
  - The Cost of Democracy - by Alexander Heard (Box 167)
  - Preliminary Manuscript (2nd Draft, 7/29/59) (Box 167)
  - Assorted Correspondence, Receipts, Newspaper Articles, Notes,Etc (Box 167)
  - Title IV: Advisory Com. - Fall Meeting (Box 167)
  - Invitations (Box 167)
  - Correspondence between A.H. & General Electric Co.) (1958-60) (Includes Publication: "Industry & the Graduate School" by J. Whitney Bunting (Box 167)
  - Assorted Publications (Elections, Negro Employment, Etc.) (Box 167)
  - Pol. Sci. 200 (Mimeographed Course Syllabus, Bibliography) (Box 167)
  - Block Print (Lithograph?) of Alexander Heard (Box 167)
  - Former Presidents & Presidential Candidates (Box 168)
  - A.H.: Campaign Cost, Presidents' Commission (Box 168)
  - Pres. CCC (Commission on Campaign Costs) (Box 168)
  - Peace Corps (Box 168)
  - Research Administrtors, National Council of Universities (Box 168)
  - Reseasrch for the Future: Doctoral Dissertation Fellowships (Box 168)
  - Social Sciences, Encyclopedia of (Box 168)
  - Gen: Universities, American Association of (AAU) (Box 168)
  - SPSA: 1962 Talk (Southern Political Science Association) (Box 168)
  - SPSA: 1962 Talk (Southern Political Science Association) (Box 168)
  - A.H.: American Heritage Foundation (Box 168)
  - Brookings Institution (Box 168)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Great Britain (Box 168)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Publications - France (Box 168)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Loose Leaf Papers - France (Box 168)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Publications - U.S.S.R, Germany, China (Box 168)
  - Publications: Democratic Digest, Time, Etc (Box 169)
  - MIP: Book Orders & Bibliography Correspondence (Box 169)
  - Bibliography: For ? (Box 169)
  - Biliogrpahy Begin (Box 169)
  - Political Studies: Book Lists, Notes, Etc (Box 169)
  - Our Six Prisons - by R.H. McCleery (Confidential Copy), January 1953 (Box 169)
  - Manuscripts: Adult Education (In Envelope) (Box 169)
  - Edison Disc (Box 169)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Terms & Concepts (Box 169)
  - Pol. Sci. 52: Switzerland (Box 169)
  - Chairman: Alexander Heard (Orange County Democratic Executive Committee Materials (1962) (In Envelope) (Box 169)
  - Newspapers, 1956-62 (Box 169)
  - Travel Maps & Tourist Publications: GA, NYC, Altanta, GA, Washington, New Jersey, Old World House, Greenbush, WI, Circus World Museum, Baraboo, WI, Villa Louis, Prairie du Chien, WI (Box 169)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (Including letter from John F. Kennedy, Septemeber 16, 1960) (Box 169)
  - Assorted Papers: Voting, Districts, Etc (Box 169)
  - Political Paraphanalia: Democratic Pins, Etc.) (Box 169)
  - Maps: Chapel Hill, Orange County (Box 169)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1957-62 (Box 169)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing - Personal (Letters, Cards, Post Cards), 1963-64 (Box 169)
  - Miscellaneous (Includes Children's Schoolwork)(Connie & Stephen) (Box 169)
  - MSS: The Costs of Democracy - by Alexander Heard (Chapters 1-7, 2nd Draft, 7/29/59) (Box 170)
  - MSS: The Costs of Democracy - by Alexander Heard (Chpaters 8-16, 2nd Draft, 6/18/59( (Box 170)
  - NASA File (Box 170)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing (1960-63) (Includes 3 Publications) (Box 170)
  - Correspondence (1962-63) (Neither Outgoing or Incoming) (Box 170)
  - Confidential Reports (Recommendation for Charles J. Parrish) (Box 170)
  - Two Papers: Presented at the Annual Meeting of the Southern Political Science Asociation (November 8-10, 1962) (Box 170)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Budget - Cuban Crisis, 12/1/62) & Edith R. Mirrielees Obituary (Box 170)
  - Publications (Box 170)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 170)
  - Virginia (Originals of Interview Memoranda) (Box 170)
  - Alabama (Interview Folder Number One) (Box 170)
  - South Carolina Folder #1 (Box 170)
  - AAUP (American Association of University Professors) (Box 171)
  - Academic Freedom (Publication, 7/31/53 & U.S.News & World Report) (Box 171)
  - Administrative Board (Box 171)
  - Agger, Bob (Box 171)
  - American Assembly (Box 171)
  - APAS Meeting (American Political Science Association) (Box 171)
  - Atlantic Urban League (Box 171)
  - Behav. Science U.N.C. Serl-Survey (Box 171)
  - Board of Public Welfare (Orange County) (Box 171)
  - Book Literature, Etc (Box 171)
  - Business Adm., School of —Adm. Board (Box 171)
  - School of Business Administration (Box 171)
  - Census Reports (Box 171)
  - Citizenship Clearing House (Box 171)
  - Civil Liberties (Box 171)
  - Committee for Economic Development (Box 171)
  - Community Council Bulletin (Box 171)
  - Congressional Quarterly (Box 171)
  - COPE: Political Memo (Box 171)
  - Communist Party (Box 171)
  - Council on Human Relations: North Carolina (Box 171)
  - Department of Political Science (Box 171)
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 171)
  - Faculty Council (Box 171)
  - Faculty Executive Committee (July 1, 1956 - July 1, 1959) (Box 171)
  - Farmers Union (Box 171)
  - Federalist Newsletter (Box 171)
  - Fortune Reprints (Box 171)
  - Freedom & Union (Box 171)
  - Friends of the Library, The (Box 171)
  - Fund for the Republic (Box 171)
  - Highlander Folk School (Box 171)
  - HR Inst.: Meetings, 1955-56 (Box 171)
  - Institute Personelle (Box 171)
  - Institute for Research in Social Science (Box 171)
  - Institutional Exchange of Personelle (Box 171)
  - IRSS: Policy Planning Committee (Box 171)
  - International Political Science Association (Box 171)
  - Luncheons, IRSS, 1952-53 (Box 171)
  - National Capitol Democratic Club (Box 171)
  - The New America (Box 171)
  - 1956 Nominating Project Prcs. — HD (Box 171)
  - Patriots of North Carolina, Inc (Box 171)
  - Personalities (Box 171)
  - Press & Politics (Box 171)
  - SSRC: Pol. Behav. Comm. (Box 171)
  - Political Statistics Comm (Box 171)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Miscellaneous Journals & Fugitive Publications (?) (Box 173)
  - Free China Review (1990-91) (7 copies)_ (Box 173)
  - Aramco World (1990-91) (4 copies) (Box 173)
  - Africa Report (1988 (3 copies) (Box 173)
  - 1986 Annual Report: Southern Africa Project (2 copies), 1987 (1 copy) (Box 173)
  - UCT News (1986) (9 copies) (Box 173)
  - South Africa/Namibia Update (19788-85) (41 copies) (Box 173)
  - AF Press Clips (1990-91) (35 copies) (Box 173)
  - TIME: The Year in Review (1977) (Includes book articles re: Walker Percy & Robert Penn Warren) (Box 173)
  - Miscellaneous Magazine Publications: Worldwatch (January/February 1989) Extensions (Fall, 1990) Vanderbilt Magazine Review: Latin (Spring 1986) Columbia (University) (Winter 1990) American Literature & the Arts (July-December 1990) (Box 173)
  - Soundings: An Interdisciplinary Journal, Spring 1990 (Box 173)
  - The Annuls (of the American Academy of Political & Social Sciences) (September 1990; March 1991; November 1991) (Box 173)
  - Daedalus: Journal of the American Academy of Arts & Sciences (Sring 1991; Winter 1991) (Box 173)
  - American Academy of Arts & Sciences (Records, 1989-90) (Box 173)
  - International Political Science Review (July 1990; January 1991; April 1991; July 1992) (Box 173)
  - American Arab Affairs (Fall 1990; Winter 1990-91) (Box 173)
  - Foreign Affairs, Spring 1991 (Box 173)
  - Foreign Affairs: America & the World 1990/91, "The Road to War" (Box 173)
  - AQ The Aspen Institute Quarterly, Autumn 1990 (Box 173)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (1987, 1988, 1990, 1991) (Box 173)
  - Council on Foreign Reltations Inc. Annual Report (1979-80, 1980-81, 1981-82, 1984-85, 1985-86) (Box 173)
  - Publication: U.S. Arms Exports: Policies & Contractors - by Paul L. Ferrari, Jeffrey W. Knopf & Raul L. Madrid (Investor Responsibility Research Center) (Box 173)
  - The United States & Japan: Changing Societies in a Changing Relationship - by Alan D. Romberg (A Conference Report; Council on Foreign Relations) (Box 173)
  - The First Annual Theodore H. White Lecture with Walter Cronkite (Harvard University) (Includes Two Notes) (Box 173)
  - After Reagan: Confronting the Changed World Economy - by C. Michael Aho & Marc Levinson (Box 173)
  - Scholarship Reconsidered: Priorities of the Professoriate - by Ernest L. Boyer (A Special Report, The Carnegie Foundation) (Box 173)
  - Choosing a College President: Opportunities & Constraints - by Judith Block McLaughlin & David Riesman (A Special Report, The Carnegie Foundation) (Box 173)
  - Annual Report: National Board of Medical Examiners (Box 173)
  - Travel Bag ("Presented to Dr. Heard on the eve of his kind visit to MAHILABHYUDAYA SEVASAMITHI, PENUMANTRA on 10/2/70 By members") (Box (Not Numbered))
  - The Ford Foundation: New Delhi (Miscellaneous Reports, Notes, Travel Instructions, Publications (4 folders) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Savannah Morning News Letter (7/31/46) Birmingham News Letter re: Civil Rights Objectives, Newspaper Clippings (9/3/48) (Manilla Envelope) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Graduate School Information (Fellowships, Etc.) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - South Eastern North Carolina Adult Education Association - Charlotte (April 9-11, 1959) (A.H. presented) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Memphis Talks: MIP (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Nuclear Power & Political Control (Duke) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Duke AAUP (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Raleigh Women's Club (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Fayetteville Talk (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Southern Pines Talk (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Statistics on Earned Degrees (MA,MS, Professional) Chapel Hill, North Carolina (Box (Not Numbered))
  - North Carolina Legislative Reapportionment (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Wallace, Schuyler (Talk to His Class) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - MSS: "Big Money in Little Sums" - by John Van Doren (Box (Not Numbered))
  - Department Seminar (Box (Not Numbered))
  - North Star '69 (July 1969) (Folder) (Box (Not Numbered))
  - "Visit of Dr. & Mrs. Alexander Heard to Ecuador & Peru" (July 6-14, 1974) (Blue 3-Ring Notebook) (Box (Not Numbered))